<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-25T15:04:25-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">VoltPopulous Consulting</title><subtitle>VoltPopulous Consulting was founded to help empower small businesses and local organizations build an infrastructure that suits their needs as well as the needs of  their users. We strive to support both our customers and Open Source communities by leveraging our knowledge and experience in Open Source solutions.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The WFH Blues</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/wfhblues" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The WFH Blues" /><published>2021-02-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/attitude</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/wfhblues">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/andrewfoulks&quot;&gt;Drew Foulks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;working-from-home-got-you-down&quot;&gt;Working from home got you down?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but work has me down lately. We’ve gotten some snow and the girls have had some time off of school and I completely missed it because I didn’t (and don’t) feel like I can always communicate my needs. Sometimes, what I need is outside help; but oftentimes the root of whatever problem I’m facing is some sort of self-defeating behavior. Some of these I’ve got pet names for, but I know that there have to be others who fall prey to these things too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we go! a deep dive into my favorite self-defeating behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tetris-mindset&quot;&gt;“The Tetris Mindset”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tetris is one of the most popular video games ever made. Nearly everyone on earth has played this game at some point in their lives. The fact that tetris is as ubiquitous as it is makes this the most easily explained self-defeating behavior. In the game of tetris, the object is to create solid rows out of several geometric arrangements of 4 squares. Once a row is completed it vanishes and you gain 100 points for your effort. The game is simple: play until no more pieces will fit into the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thinking about this for many years, I’ve come to realize that what the tetris player is constantly looking at is a monument of their own failure. That pile of squares represents everything you haven’t done yet, all of the mistakes you’ve made and the opportunities you’ve missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So why do people still play tetris?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thought on this is that because tetris is something you can put down and press pause; compare high scores with your friends; get frustrated, rage quit, then start again fresh later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very rarely does life afford you the opportunity to do &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of the things I just mentioned. But that doesn’t mean we can’t try to implement some room to do these things (or an equivalent of it) in life. My favorite cure for the Tetris Mindset is to stop working for a bit and enjoy the things that your work allows you to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-urkel-paradigm&quot;&gt;“The Urkel Paradigm”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reacting to problems at work can be harrowing at times. When your work can be destructive, every time an alert goes off panic can set in. What I’ve come to call “The Urkel paradigm” assumes that the blame is on you before you even know what really happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thought process, left unchecked, metamorphoses into an attitude where you see yourself as the most likely point of failure in everything you do. The weakest link so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do I do about this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to be perfectly honest with you my friend, I have no idea. It’s something that I struggle with every day. Low self-esteem &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; sucks, but there are ways to fight it! I use a routine as well as some things I’ve learned about myself over the years to help me not be discouraged when I perceive myself to be the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I shower and get dressed every day (even on weekends… just later…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I make it a point to eat meals (even if it’s more like a snack than a lunch, it’s better than nothing)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know right, that sounds an awful lot like the things you do to fight depression, and you’re right. They do. That’s because &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; kind of thinking can exacerbate any stress into a full blown mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-yardstick-problem&quot;&gt;“The Yardstick problem”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The yardstick problem is a problem of comparitive effort. It is probably &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; most commonly referenced problem since social media became a thing. In a nutshell, The problem is comparing yourself against people that aren’t necessarily your peers. If you’re feeling down because you can’t handle the problem as quickly as the guy who wrote the system, you’ve set yourself up for failure friend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That guy, is way better than you &lt;em&gt;at that&lt;/em&gt;, that doesn’t mean they’re better than you. I don’t know if anyone else feels this way but whenever I’m bad at something I feel bad, and I feel worse by comparison when other people are good at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wouldn’t challenge Gary Kasparov to a chess match &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;, stop trying to out-chess to Gary Kasparov.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What helps me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to take breaks and go do things I’m good at. THEN I GET TO BE THE UNREASONABLE YARDSTICK!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but in all seriousness: there’s probably someone, somewhere, who admires something you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I suffer from these harmless sounding afflictions but the struggle is real y’all. any one of these can cause major issues in anxiety, depression, and even cause executive functional issues.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">By Drew Foulks</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ansible: The Anvil and the Crucible</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/anvil-and-crucible" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ansible: The Anvil and the Crucible" /><published>2021-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/ansible</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/anvil-and-crucible">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/andrewfoulks&quot;&gt;Drew Foulks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a popular, open source, python program that can leverage ssh-keys to preform configuration management tasks on hosts that are registered to its inventory. It is agent-less, and required little in the way of configuration. It is written in Yet Another Markup Language (YAML) and is easily readable to the layperson (readable != self-documenting, IMHO).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several years of thinking about how best to describe ansible philosophies, I’ve decided to write down my attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, some basics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-ansible&quot;&gt;About Ansible&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a useful tool for the administrator tasked with maintaining a diverse environment. By standardizing processes and configuration sets across the environment, and with parallel processing effort is saved in deployment and technical debt is reduced as changes that are made to ansible processes and configuration sets are version controlled. Ansible has three separate modes of use: ad-hoc, playbook, role. Each of these modes corresponds to method of change that ansible leverages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;idempotence&quot;&gt;Idempotence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idempotence&quot;&gt;Idempotence&lt;/a&gt; is the property of certain operations in mathematics and computer science whereby they can be applied multiple times without changing the result beyond the initial application. A basic example of an idempotent operation is “turn on the lights”. The result of asking someone to “turn on the lights” is that the state of the lights will be on, regardless of their state before you asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-anvil&quot;&gt;The Anvil&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forging is the processing of metal by heating it in fire and heating or hammering it into its desired shape. This is analagous to how Ansible can be used to automate processes with the use of playbooks. Playbooks do non-standard things in a standardized way. From creating a user to installing and configuring a one off service. Playbooks and Ad Hoc usage of Ansible give the administrator the power to administer and make changes on the server / group of servers at hand, in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-ansible-ad-hoc-and-playbooks&quot;&gt;Using Ansible Ad-Hoc and Playbooks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running ansible in Ad-Hoc mode with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ansible&lt;/code&gt; allows you to implement one-off commands / module calls from the command line for any defined group / host in the inventory. In my experience this method is useful for reporting and coordinating changes due to environmental factors: e.g. moving VMs from one HA group to another for maintenance, or patching all of the vunlerable nodes of a given kind. I personally visualize this method of use as “The Anvil”. This method is well suited for responses and parallel processing can bring down response times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible playbooks, a YAML formatted job object that allows for the sequencing of automated events. Playbooks use the same &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.ansible.com/ansible/2.9/modules/modules_by_category.html&quot;&gt;ansible modules&lt;/a&gt; used for ad-hoc calls to string actions together. Playbooks contain one or more job objects that span multiple hosts to preform more complex processes. An important note about the Ansible playbook is that it is  &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; necessarily idempotent i.e. running a playbook multiple times can yield different results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-crucible&quot;&gt;The Crucible&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A crucible is used in the process of casting metal into a re-usable cast. One of the methods of mass production, raw material is heated and cast into the shape of a form. Ansible can take a server and install a standardized configuration and enforce that configuration going forward, keeping each instance of that server up-to-date with the latest role updates. This is important&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ansible-roles&quot;&gt;Ansible Roles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roles are the method Ansible uses to deploy and enforce configurations (changed back to the standard if something has changed on disk). Because they preform pre-flight checks in order to determine the state of things before issuing changes, Ansible roles are idempotent.
Roles are the odd one out here because of the fact that ansible roles are not run against a machine / group of machines but applied uniformly. Ansible roles can be assigned via host or group var, playbook, or ad hoc call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-all-this-really-means&quot;&gt;What all this really means&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a tool for system administrators that acts as both anvil and crucible; providing both the tools to create one-offs in a standardized way and allowing the administrator to cast a system to a specific role.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">By Drew Foulks</summary></entry></feed>